Hello, guys. Perfect. So yeah, today I'll be talking
สวัสดีครับทุกคน วันนี้ผมจะมาพูดถึง
about custom PostgreSQL checkpointer using LangGraph.
การใช้ PostgreSQL checkpointer แบบกำหนดเองด้วย LangGraph
It's a bit of a mouthful, but I'll try to go ahead and break
มันอาจจะฟังดูซับซ้อนหน่อย แต่ผมจะพยายามอธิบาย
it down into pieces so that you guys can kind of understand how
ให้เข้าใจง่ายๆ ว่ามันทำงานยังไง
to save data in AI application. So we can go to the next.
และวิธีการบันทึกข้อมูลในแอปพลิเคชัน AI ไปสไลด์ต่อไปได้เลยครับ
So my name is Will. I'm a founder of Reacthor.
ผมชื่อวิล เป็นผู้ก่อตั้ง Reacthor
So we basically help companies build custom AI workflows in Southeast
เราช่วยบริษัทต่างๆ สร้าง AI workflows ในเอเชียตะวันออกเฉียงใต้
Asia and also also in the US. So currently we we're we have about
และในสหรัฐอเมริกา ปัจจุบันเรามีลูกค้า
two customers here in Southeast Asia, one in the UK.
สองรายในเอเชียตะวันออกเฉียงใต้ และหนึ่งรายในสหราชอาณาจักร
And yeah, I'll tell you a little bit more about deploying your own app,
ผมจะเล่าให้ฟังเพิ่มเติมเกี่ยวกับการ deploy แอป
building your own application, especially in production using
การสร้างแอปพลิเคชันของคุณเอง โดยเฉพาะใน production
AI a little bit later. But we'll get to we'll get to
ที่ใช้ AI ในภายหลัง แต่ก่อนอื่นเราจะมาพูดถึง
talk a little bit about how link chain works first.
วิธีการทำงานของ LangChain กันก่อน
And before I start, has anybody use link chain in production Use it.
ก่อนที่ผมจะเริ่ม มีใครเคยใช้ LangChain ใน production บ้างไหมครับ
Just testing or link chain? No. Never. No one. Okay, great. Perfect.
แค่ทดสอบ หรือ LangChain? ไม่มี ไม่เคยเลย โอเค เยี่ยมมาก
Okay, let's go to the next. Okay, so I think in the first talk
ไปสไลด์ต่อไปได้เลยครับ เรื่องแรกคือ
they, they used a specific they used an SDK from OpenAI just to,
พวกเขาใช้ SDK จาก OpenAI เพื่อ
just to basically, you know, call the LLM and then go ahead and,
เรียกใช้งาน LLM และ
and then, you know, they have a specific prompt, they have the LLM
พวกเขามี prompt ที่เฉพาะเจาะจง, มี LLM,
and then they have the output. So the difference between just
และได้ output ออกมา ซึ่งความแตกต่างระหว่าง
using the SDK and using LangChain is the following.
การใช้ SDK กับการใช้ LangChain คือ
You have different types of components that you can use like tools.
คุณมี components หลายประเภทที่สามารถใช้เป็นเครื่องมือได้
For example you can use tools that
ตัวอย่างเช่น คุณสามารถใช้ tools ที่
are pre-built like searching the web. You can use tools to figure out
มีคนสร้างไว้แล้ว เช่น การค้นหาบนเว็บ คุณสามารถใช้ tools เพื่อ
if you want to find what. If you want to find out the latest,
หาข้อมูลที่ทันเหตุการณ์
the weather or or you can use custom tools for calculators,
เช่นสภาพอากาศ หรือคุณสามารถสร้าง tools เองสำหรับการคำนวณ
I'll get into the specific details of what type of tools that you can
ผมจะอธิบายรายละเอียดเพิ่มเติมเกี่ยวกับประเภทของ tools ที่คุณสามารถ
use in production, but you can also use like things like RAG for for,
ใช้ใน production ได้ แต่คุณยังสามารถใช้เทคนิค RAG สำหรับ
you know, retrieving information. And then also you have also the
การดึงข้อมูล และคุณยังสามารถ
ability to like use your chat history when you're interacting
ใช้ประวัติการแชทของคุณเมื่อคุณกำลังโต้ตอบ
with your LLM app.
กับแอป LLM ของคุณ
So for example, a lot of the times when you're using the actual SDK, you
ตัวอย่างเช่น หลายครั้งที่คุณใช้ SDK
you can't typically save your memory. So LangChain has a ability for you
มันไม่มีความสามารถในการบันทึกความจำได้ ดังนั้น LangChain จึงมีความสามารถ
to go ahead and save your memory and retrieve information from it. Okay.
ในการบันทึก memory ของคุณและดึงข้อมูลจากมัน
And has anybody here use LangGraph before? No. Okay.
มีใครเคยใช้ LangGraph บ้างไหมครับ? ไม่มี โอเค
Obviously, if you didn't if you haven't used LangChain, you're not
แน่นอน ถ้าคุณไม่เคยใช้ LangChain คุณก็คง
going to use LangGraph. Perfect. And go to go to the next slide.
ไม่เคยใช้ LangGraph ไปสไลด์ต่อไปได้เลยครับ
Okay. Cool. So what is LangGraph. So LangGraph was actually built by
LangGraph คืออะไร LangGraph ถูกสร้างขึ้นโดย
Lang Chain, the team at Lang Chain, and it's based on Pregel which
ทีม LangChain และมันอิงจาก Pregel ซึ่ง
is was built by Google. Originally Pregel was built for rerank.
ถูกสร้างขึ้นโดย Google เดิมที Pregel ถูกสร้างขึ้นเพื่อ rerank
So usually when you're reranking
ดังนั้นโดยปกติเมื่อคุณจัดอันดับเว็บไซต์ใหม่
sites and you're batching requests. So it was built to build like a
และคุณกำลังประมวลผล request แบบ batch ดังนั้นมันถูกสร้างขึ้นเพื่อสร้าง
graph database. So you can retrieve information
graph database เพื่อให้คุณสามารถดึงข้อมูล
and you can pass information very quickly.
และส่งผ่านข้อมูลได้อย่างรวดเร็ว
And so how LangGraph works is you basically have your your graph,
LangGraph ทำงานโดยมี graph
you have your node, your main node. This is just as an example.
มี node หลัก นี่เป็นเพียงตัวอย่าง
And then you have your tools. So you can search for example
และมี tools เช่น คุณสามารถค้นหา
you can search hotels. You can find the best prices in
โรงแรม หาราคาที่ดีที่สุด
case of if you're if you're if you're an employee at Agoda,
ถ้าคุณเป็นพนักงาน Agoda
you'll probably know this. And you can confirm your hotel
คุณน่าจะรู้จักสิ่งนี้ และคุณสามารถยืนยันการเลือกโรงแรม
choice and then send a payment link. And then you have your state.
และส่งลิงก์การชำระเงิน จากนั้นก็มี state
So you I guess most of you use JavaScript, right? Okay, great.
ผมเดาว่าพวกคุณส่วนใหญ่ใช้ JavaScript ใช่ไหม? โอเค เยี่ยม
You guys use React. Great. Okay. State management. Great.
พวกคุณใช้ React เยี่ยมมาก การจัดการ state เยี่ยม
That's what it is — your state. And so what you can do is you can
นั่นคือ state ของคุณ และสิ่งที่คุณทำได้คือ
save your messages, append it, and then also have your hotel choice and
บันทึกข้อความ เพิ่มข้อความ และมีตัวเลือกโรงแรม
your booking history right in there. So if we just scroll down okay.
และประวัติการจองของคุณอยู่ตรงนั้น เลื่อนลงมาหน่อยครับ
So for, for example for the travel agents
ตัวอย่างเช่น สำหรับ travel agent
that we're building at the moment, one of the requirements for it is
ที่เรากำลังสร้างอยู่ในตอนนี้ หนึ่งในข้อกำหนดคือ
that we want to find the best prices. And we want to be able to book
เราต้องการหาราคาที่ดีที่สุด และเราต้องการให้สามารถจอง
your travel agent, write directly into your app.
travel agent ของคุณได้โดยตรงในแอป
So a lot of the times when you're prompting ChatGPT under the hood,
หลายครั้งที่คุณใช้ ChatGPT
it's actually using a lot of different things,
เบื้องหลังมันใช้หลายสิ่งหลายอย่าง
like architectures that you that you might not be familiar with.
เช่นสถาปัตยกรรมที่คุณอาจไม่คุ้นเคย
We'll we'll get into details about the architecture that you can
เราจะลงรายละเอียดเกี่ยวกับสถาปัตยกรรมที่คุณสามารถ
use when you build AI apps a
ใช้เมื่อคุณสร้างแอป AI
little bit later. But this specific architecture is
ในภายหลัง แต่สถาปัตยกรรมนี้เรียกว่า
called a supervisor architecture. So essentially you have your
supervisor architecture โดยพื้นฐานแล้วคุณมี
question. It invokes a travel node. And then you have your router
คำถาม มันเรียกใช้ travel node จากนั้นคุณมี router
which is your conditional node. So you basically it runs a
ซึ่งเป็น conditional node มันจะทำ
sentiment analysis on whether or not this is actually a question
sentiment analysis ว่านี่เป็นคำถาม
regarding finding hotels. And if it does, if it is,
เกี่ยวกับการหาโรงแรมหรือไม่ และถ้าใช่
then it moves on to the next node. And then it goes ahead
มันจะไปยัง node ถัดไป และมันจะ
and invokes a ‘search hotel’. And then that invokes ‘find the best prices.’
เรียกใช้คำสั่ง search hotel จากนั้นก็ find the best prices
And then we have an interrupt.
และเรามี interrupt
So an interrupt is when the user actually makes the choice whether
interrupt คือเมื่อผู้ใช้ตัดสินใจว่า
or not they, they want to, they want to choose that hotel one.
พวกเขาต้องการเลือกโรงแรมนั้นหรือไม่
Hotel two or hotel four. Whichever hotels that they want.
โรงแรมที่สอง หรือโรงแรมที่สี่ โรงแรมใดก็ได้ที่พวกเขาต้องการ
And then that's when you're. Once you, the user has chosen that,
และเมื่อผู้ใช้เลือกแล้ว
then we can confirm the hotel choice. And then we update the state
เราสามารถยืนยันการเลือกโรงแรม และเราอัปเดต state
directly. And then we we then we then use
โดยตรง จากนั้นเราใช้
a conditional router to update the actual choice.
conditional router เพื่ออัปเดตตัวเลือก
And then we have we can send a payment link which is another tool.
และเราสามารถส่งลิงก์การชำระเงิน ซึ่งเป็น tool อีกตัวหนึ่ง
So you can think of your tool sets. And then you have your travel agent
คุณสามารถนึกถึงชุดเครื่องมือของคุณ และคุณมี travel agent
which is a which is the actual node that are connected to it.
ซึ่งเป็น node ที่เชื่อมต่อกับมัน
So your large language model has basically helpers that it can that it
ดังนั้น LLM ของคุณมีตัวช่วยที่มันสามารถ
can basically that it can basically retrieve or look for to help,
ดึงข้อมูลหรือค้นหาเพื่อช่วย
to help it out. So I think the main difference
มันได้ ผมคิดว่าความแตกต่างหลัก
is when you're building out your standard application, like at Agoda,
คือเมื่อคุณสร้างแอปพลิเคชันมาตรฐาน เช่น ที่ Agoda
you're building out your search system, your your like an application
คุณกำลังสร้างระบบการค้นหา แอปพลิเคชัน
that that we saw previously. It's all CRUD right.
ที่เราเห็นก่อนหน้านี้ มันคือ CRUD ใช่ไหม
So create read update, delete. This is a bit different because
สร้าง อ่าน อัปเดต ลบ มันแตกต่างกันเล็กน้อยเพราะ
you're actually giving power to the large language model to make
คุณกำลังให้พลังแก่ LLM ในการ
the decision to retrieve a tool or use a tool that it needs.
ตัดสินใจดึงข้อมูลหรือใช้ tool ที่มันต้องการ
So it's a bit of a shift of how you're thinking.
ดังนั้นมันจึงเป็นการเปลี่ยนแปลงวิธีคิดของคุณ
It's in terms of like thinking, if you're thinking of
ในแง่ของการคิด ถ้าคุณกำลังคิดถึง
deterministic and imperative programing, where you have conditions
การเขียนโปรแกรมแบบ declarative และ imperative ทั่วไป ซึ่งคุณมีเงื่อนไขต่างๆ
and those conditions are set by you, but actually over here you have the
ที่คุณต้องกำหนดเงื่อนไขเองทั้งหมด แต่ที่นี่คุณมี
sets of rules, and the LLM has to make a decision to use those tools,
รายการกฎต่างๆ และ LLM ต้องตัดสินใจว่าจะใช้ tools ไหน
whether or not to use those tools. So and then we can scroll
หรือไม่ใช้ tools เหล่านั้นเลย — เลื่อนลงมาหน่อยครับ
down a little bit. I don't know if you guys can see this.
ผมไม่รู้ว่าพวกคุณเห็นไหม
Is it possible to click it?
ลองคลิกดูได้ไหม
It's so small you could probably click it I think okay. Yeah.
มันเล็กมาก คุณน่าจะคลิกได้ โอเค
So here's how it works. So you basically have your state
นี่คือวิธีการทำงาน คุณมี state
right up top your checkpointer, which we'll get into a little bit
อยู่ด้านบน checkpointer ซึ่งเราจะพูดถึงในภายหลัง
later, which is your Postgres saver. And and then right after that you
ซึ่งเป็น Postgres saver และหลังจากนั้นคุณ
have your, you initialize your state and you have your travel agent.
initialize state ของคุณ และคุณมี travel agent
This is actually where you control the state.
นี่คือที่ที่คุณควบคุม state
And typically inside of that you would have different things like
และโดยทั่วไปภายในนั้นคุณจะมีสิ่งต่างๆ เช่น
your tools and then also your invocation for the graph.
tools ของคุณ และการเรียกใช้ graph
I didn't have I don't have the picture there, but if you guys
ผมไม่มีรูปภาพตรงนั้น แต่ถ้าพวกคุณ
want to talk to me later about it, I'd be happy to show you the
อยากคุยกับผมเพิ่มเติม ผมยินดีที่จะ
code and everything. And this is where you're
โชว์โค้ดให้ดู และนี่คือที่ที่คุณ
actually doing the invocation. This is Python, so sorry if you're
เรียกใช้งาน นี่คือภาษา Python ขออภัยถ้าคุณ
JavaScript developer, but Python is much better. Whoa whoa whoa whoa.
เป็นนักพัฒนา JavaScript แต่ Python ดีกว่ามาก
It is. It's easier. Come on. It's much easier.
ใช่ มันง่ายกว่ามาก
And it's performance. Okay, so anyway, this is one singular
และประสิทธิภาพก็ดีกว่า นี่คือ endpoint เดียว
endpoint that you can invoke. And and then it would find the best
ที่คุณสามารถเรียกใช้ได้ และมันจะหาราคาที่ดีที่สุด
prices and everything. So if you. Yep. And you can zoom out okay.
และข้อมูลอื่นๆ — ซูมออกได้ครับ
So let's get into what is a checkpointer.
เรามาดูกันว่า checkpointer คืออะไร
So essentially a checkpointer is is somewhere where you can store
โดยพื้นฐานแล้ว checkpointer คือที่ที่คุณสามารถจัดเก็บ
states in a graph. And the difference between saving
state ใน graph และความแตกต่างระหว่างการบันทึก
data, let's say in a standard database like I mentioned is you're
ข้อมูลใน database ทั่วไป อย่างที่ผมได้กล่าวไปคือ
doing at a basic level. CRUD, right? For for your checkpointer,
คุณกำลังทำในระดับพื้นฐาน CRUD ใช่ไหม? สำหรับ checkpointer
it's a bit different where you have a connection,
มันแตกต่างกันเล็กน้อยตรงที่คุณมี connection
which is like your PostgreSQL URL. It could be something that you're
ซึ่งก็คือ PostgreSQL URL ของคุณ มันอาจจะเป็น URL
using for like let's say on Supabase and you have the URL,
ที่คุณใช้บน Supabase
and then you have your concurrency, which is your pipeline.
และคุณมี concurrency ซึ่งก็คือ pipeline ของคุณ
So the concurrency pipeline is where you is basically where it
pipeline concurrency คือที่ที่มัน
sets up the the actual database where it creates the tables.
set up database ที่ซึ่งมันสร้างตาราง
And then if it's enabled, this is the actual part
และถ้ามันถูกเปิดใช้งาน นี่คือส่วนที่
that's a bit different than the CRUD,
แตกต่างจาก CRUD
the CRUD apps is. It batches most of the it batches
คือมันจะรวมคำสั่ง SQL
the commands from SQL like a put, tuple list, and then also writes.
เช่น put, tuple list, และ writes
So it's slightly different where every single invocation with your,
ดังนั้นมันจึงแตกต่างกันเล็กน้อยตรงที่ทุกครั้งที่เรียกใช้
your large language model or your chain will go ahead and
LLM หรือ chain ของคุณ มันจะ
batch certain requests together. And I'll show you how that works.
รวม request บางอย่างเข้าด้วยกัน และผมจะแสดงให้คุณเห็นว่ามันทำงานอย่างไร
If you go down. Perfect. Okay, so now going back to our
เลื่อนลงมา โอเค กลับไปที่ตัวอย่างของเรา
example, we have a travel agent node. So I think if you go if you
เรามี travel agent node ถ้าคุณ
scroll just a little bit up oh shit I moved that.
เลื่อนขึ้นไปนิดหน่อย
So this one this is actually the question.
นี่คือคำถาม
And then over here if you if you remember what I mentioned about
และตรงนี้ ถ้าคุณจำที่ผมพูดถึง
Checkpointer, every checkpointer has a thread
Checkpointer ได้ ทุก checkpointer มี thread
and that thread is then saved. So this you can think of as like
และ thread นั้นจะถูกบันทึก คุณสามารถคิดว่านี่เป็นเหมือน
your messages saved your message history with your agent state
ประวัติข้อความของคุณที่บันทึกไว้กับ agent state
this is where it's saved. And then so anytime you're
นี่คือที่ที่มันถูกบันทึกไว้ และทุกครั้งที่คุณ
invoking a question, let's say you want to search for
ส่งคำถาม สมมติว่าคุณต้องการค้นหา
a booking somewhere, right? It will get the current version
การจองที่ไหนสักแห่ง มันจะดึงเวอร์ชันปัจจุบัน
of the graph state. So it would run a batch for aget.
ของ graph state ดังนั้นมันจะรัน batch สำหรับ aget
And if you zoom out then you would have your conditional node, whether
และถ้าคุณซูมออก คุณจะมี conditional node ว่า
or not it's searching for hotels. And then once you get to the user
มันกำลังค้นหาโรงแรมหรือไม่ และเมื่อคุณไปถึงจุดที่ผู้ใช้
picking the actual hotel which is hotel one, this is where we're
ที่กำลังเลือกโรงแรม ซึ่งก็คือโรงแรมที่หนึ่ง นี่คือที่ที่เรา
batching operations like aget and aput where you have to get the
รวมการดำเนินการเช่น aget และ aput ที่ซึ่งคุณต้องดึงเวอร์ชันปัจจุบันของ state
actual current version of the state, and then you then update that
และจากนั้นคุณอัปเดต
the hotel choices. Hotel one. And then this is where you go
ตัวเลือกโรงแรม โรงแรมที่หนึ่ง และนี่คือที่ที่คุณ
ahead and you update the state, and then you eventually go ahead and
อัปเดต state และในที่สุด
the user approves it, and then you get your answer directly to the user.
ผู้ใช้อนุมัติ และคุณได้รับคำตอบโดยตรงถึงผู้ใช้
So let's say if you're using an SDK from OpenAI or Vertex,
สมมติว่าคุณกำลังใช้ SDK จาก OpenAI หรือ Vertex
building a building an application just like this might
การสร้างแอปพลิเคชันแบบนี้อาจ
be a bit tough just because you don't have the control flow when
ยากสักหน่อย เพราะคุณไม่มี control flow เมื่อ
you're using one singular SDK. So LangChain just allows you to
คุณใช้ SDK เดียว ดังนั้น LangChain จึงช่วยให้คุณ
give, gives you the ability to go ahead and architect your apps in a
สามารถออกแบบ workflow ให้ AI แอปของคุณ
way where you have where you have a human in the loop workflow.
ในแบบที่คุณมี human in the loop
Okay. And yeah,
โอเค
so this is this is how Checkpointer and Postgres internally are saved.
นี่คือวิธีที่ checkpointer บันทึกข้อมูลไว้ภายใน Postgres
So you have your thread ID again like I mentioned.
คุณมี thread ID อีกครั้งอย่างที่ผมได้กล่าวไป
And each thread represents a version of the state.
และแต่ละ thread แสดงถึงเวอร์ชันของ state
And actually one thing that I forgot to mention was if let's say you're on
และสิ่งหนึ่งที่ผมลืมพูดถึงคือ สมมติว่าคุณอยู่ที่
version three of the graph state, every thread has a
เวอร์ชันสามของ graph state ทุก thread มี
parent_ts which referenced the previous state of
parent_ts ซึ่งอ้างอิงถึง state ก่อนหน้าของ
the parent and child, and then a timestamp
parent และ child และ timestamp
which isn't in there. But yeah, okay. We can move. Okay.
ซึ่งไม่ได้อยู่ในนั้น โอเค เราไปต่อได้
So let me take you through a real world example.
ผมจะยกตัวอย่างในโลกจริง
We're working with Salary Hero at the moment.
เรากำลังทำงานกับ Salary Hero อยู่ในขณะนี้
So they have an issue where they're going about 20% every month per,
พวกเขามีปัญหาที่พวกเขากำลังเติบโตประมาณ 20% ทุกเดือนต่อ
you know, for per company that they're, that they're working with.
บริษัทที่พวกเขากำลังทำงานด้วย
And they have maybe about a thousand plus employees that are coming in
และพวกเขามีพนักงานประมาณหนึ่งพันคน
and and interacting with the app. And they need a lot of help,
ที่เข้ามาและโต้ตอบกับแอป และพวกเขาต้องการความช่วยเหลือมาก
meaning like they need information about loans, they need to retrieve
หมายถึง พวกเขาต้องการข้อมูลเกี่ยวกับสินเชื่อ พวกเขาต้องการดึง
information about, you know, whether or not they can take out a
ข้อมูลเกี่ยวกับว่าพวกเขาสามารถ
loan this month or the next month, and they're getting about,
กู้เงินเดือนนี้หรือเดือนหน้าได้หรือไม่ และพวกเขากำลังได้รับประมาณ
let's say, 800 requests per day. So and they only have five people,
สมมติว่า 800 คำขอต่อวัน และพวกเขามีเพียงห้าคน
five customers, a five customer support.
ฝ่ายสนับสนุนลูกค้าห้าคน
And they're only able to to they're only able to reply about
และพวกเขาสามารถตอบกลับได้เพียง
300 messages per day. So they were constrained in that
300 ข้อความต่อวัน ดังนั้นพวกเขาจึงถูกจำกัด
environment. So they try to go to different
ในสภาพแวดล้อมนั้น ดังนั้นพวกเขาจึงพยายามไปที่
vendors. But they really they really
ผู้ขายรายอื่น แต่พวกเขาไม่สามารถ
couldn't build like a custom solution because a lot of their
สร้างโซลูชันแบบกำหนดเองได้ เพราะข้อมูลของพวกเขา
data was dispersed everywhere. They had data on Excel,
กระจัดกระจายไปทั่ว พวกเขามีข้อมูลใน Excel
data on Google Sheets, pretty much everywhere.
ข้อมูลใน Google Sheets แทบทุกที่
So so basically we came in and we we first what we do is we build out a,
ดังนั้นโดยพื้นฐานแล้ว เราเข้ามาและสิ่งแรกที่เราทำคือสร้าง
we build out a graph model just like this, just to kind of
แบบจำลองกราฟแบบนี้ เพื่อ
represent like what we're what, like the different state of the flow.
แสดงสถานะต่างๆ ของ flow
This is part of it. I'm not going to show everything,
นี่เป็นเพียงส่วนหนึ่ง ผมจะไม่แสดงทั้งหมด
but you can think of the user coming in with their question with,
แต่คุณสามารถนึกภาพผู้ใช้เข้ามาพร้อมกับคำถาม
you know, sentiment analysis. Before I actually explain that
พร้อมกับ sentiment analysis ก่อนที่ผมจะอธิบาย
the one part of one part of the issue that they had is that
ปัญหาส่วนหนึ่งที่พวกเขามีคือ
their users are online. So we need to identify who the
ผู้ใช้ของพวกเขาออนไลน์ ดังนั้นเราต้องระบุตัวตน
user is. So one thing is what what they what
ผู้ใช้ สิ่งหนึ่งคือสิ่งที่พวกเขา
they did manually was they they interacted with the customer directly
ทำด้วยตนเองคือ พวกเขาโต้ตอบกับลูกค้าโดยตรง
and then try to figure out who it is, look up in the database who it is,
และพยายามหาว่าเป็นใคร ค้นหาใน database ว่าเป็นใคร
okay. Which company is it okay. Which is it. Priority one okay.
บริษัทไหน ลำดับความสำคัญหนึ่ง
And then they went ahead and replied to the user.
แล้วพวกเขาก็ตอบกลับผู้ใช้
So basically I, we basically erased all of the steps
เราลบขั้นตอนทั้งหมดนั้น
from the human that's doing that. And the first thing that we're
ที่มนุษย์ทำ สิ่งแรกที่เราทำคือ
doing is we're greeting the user. After greeting the user,
ทักทายผู้ใช้ หลังจากทักทายผู้ใช้
we're updating the state that the greeting is true.
เราอัปเดต state ว่า greeting = true
After doing that, then the then we're verifying the user.
หลังจากนั้น เราจะยืนยันตัวตนผู้ใช้
This is where this is where the large language model is.
นี่คือที่ที่ LLM ทำงาน
Then invoking authentication like so that the user can log in.
เรียกใช้คำสั่ง authentication เพื่อให้ผู้ใช้สามารถเข้าสู่ระบบได้
Once the user has logged in, we saved it in the state, and then we
เมื่อผู้ใช้เข้าสู่ระบบแล้ว เราบันทึกไว้ใน state และ
then reroute them based on priority. So it's rerouted to customer support.
เปลี่ยนเส้นทางพวกเขาตามลำดับความสำคัญ ดังนั้นจึงถูกเปลี่ยนเส้นทางไปยังฝ่ายสนับสนุนลูกค้า
Large language model that's able to then, you know, basically just
LLM ที่สามารถ
give information to the user. One of the things once they're
ให้ข้อมูลแก่ผู้ใช้ สิ่งหนึ่งเมื่อพวกเขา
routed over here, I'm not sure if you guys are familiar
ถูกเปลี่ยนเส้นทางมาที่นี่ — ผมไม่แน่ใจว่าพวกคุณคุ้นเคย
with the term called crews. So basically you have a master
กับคำว่า crews หรือไม่ — โดยพื้นฐานแล้วคุณมี master
agent if you go right up top, I think, okay.
agent ถ้าคุณเลื่อนขึ้นไปด้านบน
So you determine whether what what question it is,
คุณกำหนดว่าคำถามคืออะไร
and then you have a master agent. And that master agent is then
และคุณมี master agent และ master agent นั้น
able to then give it basically pass that information,
สามารถส่งต่อข้อมูลนั้น
pass it to the right agent. So company policy, general info,
ส่งต่อไปยัง agent ที่ถูกต้อง เช่น นโยบายบริษัท ข้อมูลทั่วไป
getting a loan, delaying payments. And then that master agent has tools.
การขอสินเชื่อ การชะลอการชำระเงิน และ master agent นั้นมี tools
If you guys remember before about tools those tools have
ถ้าคุณจำได้ tools เหล่านั้นมี
different types of use cases. So tools they retrieve
กรณีการใช้งานที่แตกต่างกัน tools จะดึง
information from Google. They retrieve information from
ข้อมูลจาก Google ดึงข้อมูลจาก
sheets. So they do a lot of customization
sheets พวกเขาทำการปรับแต่งมากมาย
to then reply to the user like for example delay payments.
เพื่อตอบกลับผู้ใช้ เช่น การชะลอการชำระเงิน
So they get like an influx of delay payments. That's coming in.
พวกเขาได้รับคำขอชะลอการชำระเงินจำนวนมาก
What we do is like we notice, okay, there's a delay payment.
สิ่งที่เราทำคือ เราสังเกตเห็นว่า มีการชะลอการชำระเงิน
We then trigger a tool that's that, then replies that, then sends an
จากนั้นเราเรียกใช้ tool ที่ตอบกลับและส่ง
email to the customer support team like, hey, there's about 800
อีเมลไปยังทีมสนับสนุนลูกค้าว่า มีผู้ใช้ประมาณ 800 คน
users that are that are asking for there that are basically that are,
ที่กำลังขอ
that are that have delayed payment. And so we need to you need to
ชะลอการชำระเงิน ดังนั้นเราต้อง
basically look at that. So yeah this is a different ways
ดูแลเรื่องนี้ นี่เป็นวิธีที่แตกต่างกัน
you can kind of architect it. If you go down a little bit you might
ที่คุณสามารถออกแบบได้ — ถ้าคุณเลื่อนลงไปอีกหน่อย
have to exit out of the thing. Yeah. So just to kind of give you a
และออกจากตรงนี้ — เพื่อให้คุณ
explanation of, of how you build these kinds of applications,
เข้าใจวิธีการสร้างแอปพลิเคชันประเภทนี้
if you go on langchain.com, you can, you can kind of like take a look.
คุณสามารถไปที่ langchain.com
But once you get to LangGraph it might get a little bit complex.
แต่เมื่อคุณไปถึง LangGraph มันอาจจะซับซ้อนขึ้นเล็กน้อย
So I would recommend just going through the documentation like
ดังนั้นผมขอแนะนำให้อ่านเอกสาร
thoroughly to understand. But the very first part that I
อย่างละเอียดเพื่อทำความเข้าใจ แต่ส่วนแรกที่ผม
mentioned, when this is the use case for Salary Hero,
กล่าวถึง เมื่อนี่คือกรณีการใช้งานสำหรับ Salary Hero
the company we're working with is we greet the user first.
บริษัทที่เรากำลังทำงานด้วยคือ เราทักทายผู้ใช้ก่อน
This is a singular LLM with no tools, just greeting the user.
นี่คือ LLM เดี่ยวที่ไม่มี tools เลย เพียงแค่ทักทายผู้ใช้
The second architecture is called is a basic supervisor agent,
สถาปัตยกรรมที่สองเรียกว่า basic supervisor agent
which has a supervisor and tools that it can use to basically talk to the
ซึ่งมี supervisor และ tools ที่สามารถใช้พูดคุยกับ
user and verifying who the user is. And then you have crews and
ผู้ใช้และยืนยันตัวตนผู้ใช้ และคุณมี crews
those crews you could think of. I don't know if you're a teacher
คุณสามารถนึกถึง crews ได้ สมมติว่าเป็นครู
and you have different types of, you know, helpers that are there.
และคุณมีผู้ช่วยเกี่ยวกับเรื่องต่างๆ
One is changing the diapers of the students, and the other is
คนหนึ่งเปลี่ยนผ้าอ้อมนักเรียน อีกคน
actually teaching the students and assisting the students.
สอนนักเรียนและช่วยเหลือนักเรียน
The teacher can invoke different tools, different people that
ครูสามารถเรียกใช้ tools ต่างๆ คนต่างๆ
they have, that she has in her tool set to retrieve information
ที่มีในชุดเครื่องมือ เพื่อดึงข้อมูล
or give information. So this is the same thing when
หรือให้ข้อมูล นี่เป็นสิ่งเดียวกันเมื่อ
you have hierarchical crew teams. But in that case, that would actually
คุณมีทีม crew แบบลำดับชั้น แต่ในกรณีนั้น
be the principal doing that. And this is a good paper to read
จะเป็นครูใหญ่ที่ทำสิ่งนั้น และนี่เป็นบทความที่ดีที่ควรอ่าน
if you've never if you've never built these kinds of system before,
ถ้าคุณไม่เคยสร้างระบบประเภทนี้มาก่อน
you're not going to understand it. I didn't understand shit.
คุณจะไม่เข้าใจมัน ผมไม่เข้าใจอะไรเลย
I just put it on ChatGPT and explain this. And then.
ผมแค่ใส่ลงใน ChatGPT และให้มันอธิบายสิ่งนี้ให้
But it's great. It's honestly it gives you it
แต่มันเยี่ยมมาก มันทำให้คุณ
gives you a perspective on how you can build like these,
มีมุมมองเกี่ยวกับวิธีการสร้าง
these like multi-agent systems. A lot of the anytime I say I say
ระบบ multi-agent เหล่านี้ ทุกครั้งที่ผมพูดถึง
anything about like, oh, I'm building a customer support agent,
การสร้าง customer support agent
like, oh wow, this must be easy. But the hardest part is the fact
มันอาจจะดูง่าย แต่ส่วนที่ยากที่สุดคือ
that, like information is dispersed depending on the organization
ข้อมูลกระจัดกระจายไปทั่ว ขึ้นอยู่กับองค์กร
and building something, custom is what they're looking for.
และการสร้างเครื่องมือเฉพาะสำหรับลูกค้า คือสิ่งที่พวกเขากำลังมองหา
Okay. Thank you. Yeah. Again. Reacthor. So we're on we're on LinkedIn.
ขอบคุณครับ Reacthor เราอยู่บน LinkedIn
We're these are my my email if you want to reach out.
นี่คืออีเมลของผม ถ้าคุณต้องการติดต่อ
If you want to talk a little bit more about what I, what I've been
ถ้าคุณต้องการพูดคุยเพิ่มเติมเกี่ยวกับสิ่งที่ผม
mentioning during this talk, great. If you want me to showcase some
พูดถึงในระหว่างการพูดคุยนี้ ยินดีครับ ถ้าคุณต้องการให้ผมแสดง
examples of applications that I'm building currently with companies,
ตัวอย่างแอปพลิเคชันที่ผมกำลังสร้างอยู่กับบริษัทต่างๆ
great. I'll do that for you. And if you if you want to. Yeah.
ยินดีครับ และถ้าคุณ
If you want to talk anytime I'm here. All right.
ต้องการพูดคุย ผมอยู่ที่นี่
Thank you
ขอบคุณครับ